Menu[Search](https://www.wsws.org/en/search)

Latest[Profile](https://www.wsws.org/en/profile)

English

Menu[Search](https://www.wsws.org/en/search)

Latest[Profile](https://www.wsws.org/en/profile)

* 

); }

Privacy Statement

Effective date: November 1, 2018

World Socialist Web Site, Inc. ("us", "we", or "our") operates the wsws.org website (the "Service").

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

#### Definitions

**Service**

Service is the wsws.org website operated by World Socialist Web Site, Inc.

**Personal Data**

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

**Usage Data**

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

**Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your device (computer or mobile device).

**Data Controller**

Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.

**Data Processors (or Service Providers)**

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

**Data Subject (or User)**

Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

#### Information Collection and Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

**Types of Data Collected**

_Personal Data_

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

* Email address
* First name and last name
* Phone number
* Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
* Cookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

_Usage Data_

We may also collect information on how the Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

_Tracking Cookies Data_

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

* **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
* **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
* **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

#### Use of Data

World Socialist Web Site uses the collected data for various purposes:

* To provide and maintain our Service
* To notify you about changes to our Service
* To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
* To provide customer support
* To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
* To monitor the usage of our Service
* To detect, prevent and address technical issues
* To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

#### Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), World Socialist Web Site legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.

World Socialist Web Site may process your Personal Data because:

* We need to perform a contract with you
* You have given us permission to do so
* The processing is in our legitimate interests and is not overridden by your rights
* For payment processing purposes
* To comply with the law

#### Retention of Data

World Socialist Web Site will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

World Socialist Web Site will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

#### Browser Data

While using our website, information is automatically saved on our servers in log files that your browser transmits to us. These include the name and version of the browser, the operating system used, the host name and IP address of the accessing computer, the referrer URL (previously visited page) and the time of the server request.

This logging is done for security reasons. The data is stored for a maximum of two weeks and then deleted automatically. The data will not be deleted if, in the opinion of the World Socialist Web Site, they provide information about attacks on the World Socialist Web Site, their information and communication technology or persons or threats of such attacks. In that case the World Socialist Web Site will promptly clarify and then delete the data or take necessary technical or legal steps to avert the attacks or threats.

#### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

**Matomo**

We use Matomo, an open source software for the statistical analysis of visitor access. Matomo stores cookies in your browser for analysis purposes. The information generated by these cookies about your use of the website is stored on our servers. Your IP address will be anonymized immediately after processing and prior to its storage. The information generated by the cookie about your use of our website will not be disclosed to third parties. You can prevent the use of cookies in the settings of your browser (see also Cookies).

If you do not agree with the storage and evaluation of this data from your visit, then you can object to the storage and use below at any time. In this case, a so-called opt-out cookie is stored in your browser, with the result that Matomo does not collect any session data. Attention: If you delete your cookies, this means that the opt-out cookie is also deleted and may need to be reactivated by you.

**Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

**SharpSpring**

Our website uses “SharpSpring” software to collect information about your use of our site, which we then use to learn about your interests and market products and services to you via phone, email or through our website. SharpSpring can only collect personally identifiable information if you provide your information through a form submission. However, it can collect non-personal information, such as IP addresses, browser types, system types, and the referring URLs. It also assigns your device a unique user ID, which can then be used to track the content and pages that you access, as well as the frequency and duration of your visits to our site.

SharpSpring has chosen to take part in and certify its adherence to the E.U.-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. You can read more about the steps SharpSpring has taken to protect the privacy of your information here: [https://sharpspring.com/legal/us-eu-privacy-notice/](https://sharpspring.com/legal/us-eu-privacy-notice/)

While SharpSpring plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but SharpSpring. SharpSpring’s ability to use and share information collected by their software about your visits to our site is restricted by SharpSpring’s Privacy Policy: [https://sharpspring.com/legal/privacy/](https://sharpspring.com/legal/privacy/). You can prevent SharpSpring from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser.

#### Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to the United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

World Socialist Web Site will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

#### Disclosure of Data

**Disclosure for Law Enforcement**

Under certain circumstances, World Socialist Web Site may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

**Legal Requirements**

World Socialist Web Site may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary:

* To comply with a legal obligation
* To protect and defend the rights or property of World Socialist Web Site
* To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
* To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
* To protect against legal liability

#### Security of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. World Socialist Web Site aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

**The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you.** Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.

**The right of rectification.** You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.

**The right to object.** You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.

**The right of restriction.** You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.

**The right to data portability.** You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.

**The right to withdraw consent.** You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where World Socialist Web Site relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

#### Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

**Payments**

We may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).

We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.

The payment processors we work with are:

_PayPal or Braintree_

Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at [https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full](https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)

**Commenting system (Disqus)**

Our website uses the Disqus annotation system provided by Disqus Inc. of San Francisco, USA. By signing up, you can comment on any website that uses Disqus as a commenting system. Disqus privacy information can be found at:

https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy

Disqus Inc. has officially submitted to the "EU US Privacy Shield":

[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TRkEAAW&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TRkEAAW&status=Active)

Registration with Disqus is either via a separate Disqus user account or via an existing user account on Facebook, Twitter or Google Plus. When registering with a user account for one of these social media offers, the respective provider will also collect and process your usage data for the Disqus functions. Please take note of the privacy information of the respective provider. We also allow commenting as a guest, but then some features are not available.

Disqus sends us the user's email address and the IP address used when entering a comment. We use this information solely for the purpose of contacting you in connection with your use of Disqus, for example, for any queries you may have about a comment. We do not pass on this information to third parties.

**Embedded content from YouTube, Facebook and SoundCloud**

Our website includes content from YouTube, Facebook and SoundCloud, which save cookies in your browser when you visit the respective page. The content and use of these cookies are beyond our control. Please take note of the privacy information of the respective provider. You can prevent the storage of these cookies in the settings of your browser (see also Cookies).

These providers will transfer the access data to the United States of America. Insofar, the incorporation of iframe corresponds to a visit to a linked page. Which data is transmitted depends also on the specific software used for the access and its configuration.

_YouTube_

YouTube is operated by Google and embedded on individual pages of the website in an iframe. Depending on the web browser used, access to the corresponding content from YouTube will be made during the display of the website page or only at the explicit request. This makes it possible to play videos.

For privacy, we refer to the Google Privacy Policy & Terms of Use page:

Google has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield:

[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI)

_Facebook_

Facebook is embedded on individual pages of the website in an iframe. Depending on the web browser used, the access to the corresponding content of Facebook takes place during the display of the page of the website or only on explicit request. This makes it possible to play videos.

Regarding data protection on Facebook, we refer to the "Data Policy" of Facebook:

Facebook has officially submitted to the "EU-US Privacy Shield":

[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)

_SoundCloud_

SoundCloud is a service of SoundCloud Limited, Rheinsberger Str. 76/77, 10115 Berlin. The legal domicile of the company is in the United Kingdom:

c / o JAG Shaw Baker, Berners House, 47-48 Berners Street, London W1T 3NF, UK.

SoundCloud is embedded on individual pages of the website in an iframe . Depending on the web browser used, access to the relevant content of SoundCloud will be made during the display of the website page or only at the explicit request. This allows playback of audio content.

For data protection, please refer to the SoundCloud Privacy Protection page:

[https://help.soundcloud.com/hc/en/articles/115003570428-privacy-bei-SoundCloud](https://help.soundcloud.com/hc/en/articles/115003570428-privacy-bei-SoundCloud)

#### Links to Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

#### Children's Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 16 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 16. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

#### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

* By email: [comments@wsws.org](mailto:comments@wsws.org)

#### Data Protection Officer

Andrew Petrov  
PO Box 48377  
Oak Park, MI 48237  
Phone: (248) 264-3735  
Email: comments@wsws.org

© 1998-2024 World Socialist Web Site. All rights reserved.

[Home](https://www.wsws.org/en "Home")[About](https://www.wsws.org/en/special/pages/icfi/wsws.html "About")[Contact](https://www.wsws.org/en/special/pages/contact.html "Contact")[Privacy Statement](https://www.wsws.org/en/special/privacy.html "Privacy Statement")Privacy Settings
